Mohammed Al-Najjar

Frontend Engineer (ReactJS) with **3+ years** of experience. Strong ownership mindset, proficient in frontend technologies, excellent communication and collaboration skills, and a passion for learning and adapting to new technologies.

Syria, Damascus mohamadnajjar934@gmail.com +963938718838 <u>LinkedIn</u>

WORK EXPERIENCE

Alfahd Regional Company

Frontend Engineer

Syria, Damascus (onsite)

FEB 2023 - PRESENT

- Optimized websites for improved speed and performance.
- Contributed ideas during brainstorming sessions for new features or improvements to existing ones.
- Collaborated with UX designers to create seamless user experiences.
- Implemented responsive web designs for optimal viewing on various devices.
- Fixed bugs and resolved technical issues reported by users or team members.
- Prioritized tasks effectively to meet deadlines while maintaining high-quality work output.
- Participated in code reviews to improve code quality and share knowledge among teammates.
- Engaged in quality assurance testing with emphasis on troubleshooting performance issues.
- Evaluated new technologies, frameworks and libraries to support high-level products.
- Assisted with maintenance and upkeep of front end applications.
- Mentored junior front-end developers, helping them grow their skills and knowledge within the team.

Freelance (Remote)

Frontend Engineer

Syria, Damascus

JAN2023 - MAY 2023

- Regularly communicated project progress and updates to team leads or clients as needed.
- Keep up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies to maintain a competitive edge.
- Proactively identified areas of improvement within existing projects and offered solutions.
- Developed user-friendly website interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

TECHNOLOGIES

Stack

ReactJs, NextJS TypeScript,Bootstrap, JQuery, Tailwind,HTML5, CSS3, JS

Other

Component Lifecycle Methods, Functional Components, Class Components, React Router, PropTypes, Error Boundaries, Code Splitting, Lazy Loading, Suspense, Refs, Portals, Higher-Order Components (HOCs), Render Props, Custom Hooks, Context API, React.memo, useCallback, useMemo, useReducer, JavaScript (ES6+), Redux, Context API, React Hooks, GraphQL, RESTful APIs,Webpack, Git/GitHub,, Responsive Design

Personal Skills

- Bug Resolution
- Problem-Solving
- Data Security
- User Acceptance Testing
- Web Components Development
- Project Estimations
- Troubleshooting
- Code debugging
- Time estimates
- Technical Solutions Development
- Deadline Adherence
- UI updates
- Full Software Development Lifecycle
- Team work

Quisters Solutions

Frontend Engineer

Germany, Velbert, North Rhine-Westphalia

APR 2021 - DEC 2022

- Designed, implemented and tested software solutions and integrated with internal and external services.
- Worked with various teams and stakeholders to create and maintain digital experiences for multiple company products.
- Troubleshooting customer-reported issues in applications and providing support.
- Contributed to digital technology projects from concept to implementation.
- Translated design mockups into responsive web pages using pixel-perfect techniques

EDUCATION

Damascus University, Computer Science

Syria, Damascus

2018-2022

PROJECTS

winshakes.com (2024).E-commerce project. Frontend ReactJs developer, ReactJs, NextJS, TypeScript Bootstrap , website and Admin dashboard
Laimonah (2023) E-commerce project. Frontend ReactJs developer ,ReactJs, NextJS, TypeScript Tailwind , website and admin dashboard

<u>rentchicken.net(2023)</u> E-commerce project. Frontend ReactJs developer ,ReactJs , Bootstrap website and admin dashboard

BookSmm.net (2022) social media management website. Frontend HTML, CSS JavaScript Bootstrap , website and admin dashboard

LANGUAGES

Arabic native
English C2, fluent
French A1, beginner

CERTIFICATES

- Meta Front-End Developer
 Professional Certificate
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Full-Stack Web Development with React Specialization
- Advanced React and Redux:
 2021 Edition
- Become a React Developer Nanodegree Program